A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration YouTube Channel Videos, 2008-2010
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration YouTube Channel Videos, 2008-2010
The Library of Virginia
51918
63 videos.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
These videos were originally posted onto YouTube by Gov. Kaine's Webmaster. Between 2008 and 2010, Library of Virginia staff downloaded the videos using GetTube software and Perian Web developer's toolkit.
Historical Information
Timothy M. Kaine was Virginia's 70th governor. He served from January 2006 to January 2010.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 63 videos that were originally posted onto YouTube by Governor Tim Kaine's Webmaster between March 2008 and January 2010. Governor Kaine formally announced the creation of the governor's YouTube channel in a 6 May 2008 press release.
The videos are listed by upload date. Included are vidoes of news conferences, transportation town hall meetings, cabinet day events, the 2008 dedication of the Virginia Civil Rights Memorial, Governor Kaine's statement on granting clemency to the Norfolk Four, and Governor Kaine's 2009 State of the Commonwealth address.
Related Material
Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal
Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010.
Timothy M. Kaine Administration (2006-2010) Cabinet Weekly Reports
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Governor, Records, 2005-2009.
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Chief of Staff, Records, 2006-2009.
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records, 2001-2009 (bulk 2006-2009)
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Policy Office, Records, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Press Office, Records, 2004-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Senior Advisor to the Governor for Workforce Records, 2006-2009.
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Latino Liaison Records, 2004-2009.
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Administration, 1995-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, 2002-2010 (bulk 2005-2009.
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 2005-2010.
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources, 1999-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Technology, 2000-2009 (bulk 2006-2009).
Contents List
- YouTube Videos, 2008-2010., Extent: 63 videos.
  - 1. Governor Kaine - Energy Share PSA, 2008.
    Governor Kaine talks about ways Virginians can conserve energy. Uploaded 21 April 2008.
    30 seconds
  - 2. Gov. Kaine's Opening Remarks, Martinsville Town Hall, 26 March 2008.
    Governor Kaine's opening remarks at the town hall meeting in Martinsville, March 26, 2008. Uploaded on 23 April 2008.
    38:58 minutes
  - 3. Questions for Gov. Kaine, Martinsville Town Hall, Part 1, 26 March 2008.
    Part 1 of Q and A with Governor Kaine at the town hall meeting in Martinsville, March 26, 2008. Uploaded 24 April 2008.
    26:16 minutes
  - 4. Questions for Gov. Kaine, Martinsville Town Hall, Part 2, 26 March 2008.
    Part 2 of Q and A with Governor Kaine at the town hall meeting in Martinsville, March 26, 2008. Uploaded 24 April 2008.
    23:19 minutes
  - 5. Gov. Kaine and Martinsville High School Students, 26 March 2008.
    Governor Kaine speaks with students before his town hall meeting at Martinsville High School, March 26, 2008. Uploaded 24 April 2008.
    12:35 minutes
  - 6. National Employee Health and Fitness Day, 2008.
    Governor Kaine speaks about National Employee Health and Fitness Day and encourages workers in Virginia to walk for fitness on Wednesday May 21, 2008. Uploaded 2 May 2008.
    37 seconds
  - 7. Governor Kaine Unveils Transportation Plan, 12 May 2008.
    On May 12, 2008, Governor Timothy M. Kaine released details of his transportation plan and called for a special session of the General Assembly to address transportation on June 23. Uploaded 12 May 2008.
    26:03 minutes
  - 8. Governor Kaine - Woodbridge Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 13 May 2008.
    Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Woodbridge, VA on May 13, 2008. Uploaded on 14 May 2008.
    29:35 minutes
  - 9. Governor Kaine - Marion Transportation Town Hall, 20 May 2008.
    Governor Kaine's opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Marion, VA on May 20, 2008. Uploaded 21 May 2008.
    29:02 minutes
  - 10. Staunton Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 22 May 2008.
    Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Staunton, VA on May 22, 2008. Uploaded 28 May 2008.
    35:33 minutes
  - 11. Staunton Transportation Town Hall - Q and A, 22 May 2008.
    Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Staunton, VA on May 22, 2008. Uploaded 28 May 2008.
    42:30 minutes
  - 12. Higher Education Bond Bill Signing, 29 May 2008.
    Virginia's Governor, Tim Kaine, delivers remarks and signs the higher education bond bill from the 2008 General Assembly session. Uploaded 29 May 2008.
    29:45 minutes
  - 13. Sexual Violence Bill Signing, 2 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine ceremonially signs legislation from the 2008 General Assembly session regarding Virginia's efforts to prevent and respond to sexual violence. Uploaded 2 June 2008.
    20:20 minutes
  - 14. Animal Welfare Bill Signing, 4 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine ceremonially signs several animal welfare bills from the 2008 General Assembly session. The bill signing took place at the Richmond SPCA. Uploaded 5 June 2008.
    25:11 minutes
  - 15. Radford Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 4 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Radford, VA on June 4, 2008. Uploaded 5 June 2008.
    40:57 minutes
  - 16. Radford Transportation Town Hall - Q and A, 4 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Radford, VA on June 4, 2008. Uploaded 6 June 2008.
    53:17 minutes
  - 17. Danville Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 7 June 2008.
    Danville Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks. Uploaded 9 June 2008.
    41:11 minutes
  - 18. Danville Transportation Town Hall - Q and A, 7 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Danville, VA on June 7, 2008. Uploaded 10 June 2008.
    23:29 minutes
  - 19. CNX Gas Corporation Announcement, 11 June 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Kaine makes a news announcement with CNX Gas Corporation. Uploaded 11 June 2008.
    31:10 minutes
  - 20. Leesburg Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 11 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Leesburg VA on June 11, 2008. Uploaded 12 June 2008.
    39:01 minutes
  - 21. Leesburg Transportation Town Hall - Q and A, 11 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Leesburg VA on June 11, 2008. Uploaded 12 June 2008.
    31:32 minutes
  - 22. Electronic Health Record News Conference, 11 June 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Timothy M. Kaine joins U.S. Health and Human Services Secretary Michael Leavitt for an announcement about the selection of an Electronic Records Demonstration Site. Uploaded 13 June 2008.
    24:47 minutes
  - 23. Joint Transportation Special Session of the General Assembly, 23 June 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Tim Kaine addresses the Joint Transportation Special Session of the General Assembly on June 23, 2008. Uploaded on 23 June 2008.
    25:25 minutes
  - 24. Hopewell Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 16 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Hopewell VA on June 16, 2008. Uploaded 25 June 2008.
    39:44 minutes
  - 25. Hopewell Transportation Town Hall Q and A, 16 June 2008.
    Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Hopewell VA on June 16, 2008. Uploaded 25 June 2008.
    39:29 minutes
  - 26. Fredericksburg Transportation Town Hall - Opening Remarks, 19 June 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Kaine delivers opening remarks during the transportation town hall in Fredericksburg, VA. The meeting was held on June 19, 2008. Uploaded on 26 June 2008.
    36:59 minutes
  - 27. Fredericksburg Transportation Town Hall - Q and A, 19 June 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Kaine takes questions during the transportation town hall in Fredericksburg, VA. The meeting was held on June 19, 2008. Uploaded 26 June 2008.
    40:07 minutes
  - 28. VA Civil Rights Memorial - Dedication - Opening Speakers, 21 July 2008.
    Opening speakers at the Virginia Civil Rights Dedication Celebration include the Honorable Dwight Jones, Nikki Giovanni, Lisa Collis, Julian Bond, and The Honorable Viola Baskerville. Uploaded 21 July 2008.
    29:25 minutes
  - 29. Virginia Civil Rights Memorial - Dedication - Unveiling, 21 July 2008.
    Virginia's Governor, Timothy M. Kaine, delivers remarks and, assisted by Blair Underwood, unveils the Virginia Civil Rights memorial on the Capital grounds of Richmond, VA. Uploaded 21 July 2008.
    15:28 minutes
  - 30. FAMIS - TV Ad - 1, August 2008.
    Public Service Announcement for Virginia's Families Access to Medical Insurance Security plan. FAMIS provides health insurance for uninsured children in Virginia. Uploaded 21 August 2008.
    0:30 minutes
  - 31. FAMIS - TV Ad - Teen, August 2008.
    0:40 minutes
  - 32. 'Think! Don't Drink' Underage Drinking Initiative, September 2008.
    In an effort to curb underage drinking in the Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor Kaine launched the 'Think! Don't Drink' initiative. Uploaded 17 September 2008.
    1:38 minutes
  - 33. Coves Conference, 19 September 2008.
    Virginia's Governor Tim Kaine delivers introductory remarks at the 2008 Commonwealth of Virginia Energy and Sustainability Conference. Uploaded 19 September 2008.
    27:06 minutes
  - 34. Iraqi Veterans License Plate Bill Signing, 25 September 2008.
    Governor Kaine ceremonially signs HB 6022, allowing for the creation of license plates to honor the veterans of Operation Iraqi Freedom. Uploaded 25 September 2008.
    23:53 minutes
  - 35. Budget News Conference, 9 October 2008.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine announces measures to respond to Virginia's budget shortfall. Uploaded 9 October 2008.
    30:10 minutes
  - 36. Society of Environmental journalists Annual Meeting, 15 October 2008.
    Governor Kaine addresses the 18th Annual Meeting of the Society of Environmental journalists, hosted by Virginia Tech. Over 1,000 journalists and government officials were expected during the week-long event. Uploaded 16 October 2008.
    5:49 minutes
  - 37. Cabinet Community Day - Urban Search and Rescue, 14 October 2008.
    As part of the Governor's tenth Cabinet Community Day on October 14, 2008, he and members of his cabinet visited Virginia Task Force 1, the Fairfax Fire and Rescue Department's Urban Search and Rescue team. Uploaded 23 October 2008.
    11:36 minutes
  - 38. Cabinet Community Day - GED, 14 October 2008.
    As part of the Governor's tenth Cabinet Community Day on October 14, 2008, he and members of his cabinet visited W.T. Woodson High School, home of the Fairfax County and Adult Community GED program. Uploaded 24 October 2008.
    9:26 minutes
  - 39. Real World Design Challenge Press Conference, 24 October 2008.
    Virginia's Governor, Timothy M. Kaine, joins public and private partners to discuss the U.S. Department of Energy's 2008 real World Design Challenge. Uploaded 24 October 2008.
    25:48 minutes
  - 40. Cabinet Community Day-PSTOC, 14 October 2008.
    As part of the Governor's tenth Cabinet Community Day on October 14, 2008, he and members of his cabinet visit Fairfax County's new McConnell Public Safety and Transportation Operations Center. Uploaded 28 October 2008.
    5:48 minutes
  - 41. Cabinet Community Day - Waste to Energy Facility, 14 October 2008.
    As part of the Governor's tenth Cabinet Community Day on October 15, 2008, he and members of his cabinet toured the I-95 Energy/Resource Recovery Facility in Lorton, Virginia. Uploaded 10 November 2008.
    9:18 minutes
  - 42. Cabinet Community Day - VA Department of Forestry Headquarters, 13 November 2008.
    As part of his eleventh Cabinet Community Day, Governor Kaine and members of his Cabinet visited the headquarters of the Virginia Department of Forestry. Uploaded 18 November 2008.
    13:33 minutes
  - 43. Cabinet Community Day - Delta Springs Farm, 13 November 2008.
    As part of his eleventh Cabinet Community Day, Governor Kaine and members of his Cabinet toured Delta Springs Farm, and environmentally sensitive poultry and cattle farm. Uploaded 21 November 2008.
    11:04 minutes
  - 44. Governor Kaine announces Renew Virginia Initiative, 11 December 2008.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine kicks off his Renew Virginia Initiative, which will include legislative and executive actions to make Virginia a leader in energy conservation and efficiency and protecting the environment. Uploaded 11 December 2008.
    18:59 minutes
  - 45. Governor Kaine's speech at the Woodrow Wilson Community Center, 13 November 2008.
    As part of his eleventh Cabinet Community Day, Governor Kaine and members of his Cabinet toured the exercise trail at the Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center, the first state-owned and operated facility comprehensive rehabilitation center in the country. Uploaded 18 December 2008.
    18:11 minutes
  - 46. Governor Kaine and Cabinet Tour Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center, 13 November 2008.
    As part of his eleventh Cabinet Community Day, Governor Kaine and members of his Cabinet toured the exercise trail at the Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center, the first state-owned and operated facility comprehensive rehabilitation center in the country. Uploaded 19 December 2008.
    4:29 minutes
  - 47. 2009 State of the Commonwealth, 14 January 2009.
    Governor Kaine delivers the annual address to the Joint Assembly outlining fiscal responsibility, his budget proposal, investments to stimulate growth, green jobs, and his renew Virginia initiative. Uploaded 19 January 2009.
    37:03 minutes
  - 48. Groundbreaking Agreement to Ban Smoking in Restaurants, 5 February 2009.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine and key leaders in the Virginia General Assembly announced a landmark agreement to pass a statewide smoking ban in Virginia's bars and Restaurants. Uploaded 5 February 2009.
    15:44 minutes
  - 49. Stimulus.Virginia.gov, 2009.
    Governor Kaine welcomes users to the Commonwealth of Virginia's stimulus site. Uploaded 11 March 2009.
    1:41 minutes
  - 50. Governor Kaine News Conference on Action on Legislation passed in General Assembly, 30 March 2009.
    Governor Kaine held a news conference today to discuss action on legislation passed during the General Assembly Session. Topics include expanded unemployment benefits. Uploaded 30 March 2009.
    35:53 minutes
  - 51. Governor Kaine Signs Restaurant Smoking Ban, 9 March 2008.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine joined Senator Ralph Northam (D-Norfolk), Delegate john Cosgrove (R-Chesapeake), other legislative supporters, public health advocates, and other stakeholders to sign legislation banning smoking in bars and restaurants. Uploaded 30 March 2009.
    25:10 minutes
  - 52. Virginia on iTunes U launch, 7 April 2009.
    Building on a number of recent initiatives designed to take learning beyond the classroom Governor Timothy M. Kaine today announced the official launch of the Virginia on iTunes. Uploaded 7 April 2009.
    28:07 minutes
  - 53. June, 2009 - Cabinet Community Day - VEC Office Visit, 5 June 2009.
    Governor Kaine and members of his Cabinet visit state employees and members of the public at the VEC office in Norton, VA. Uploaded 12 June 2009.
    9:07 minutes
  - 54. Governor's Housing Forum, 8 June 2009.
    On June 8, 2009 Governor Kaine hosted a forum featuring members of the Virginia congressional delegation on the housing foreclosure rate in Virginia and proposal on how to reduce it. Uploaded 19 June 2009.
    2:09:24 minutes
  - 55. STEM For Life Governors Academy, 5 June 2009.
    During his Southwest VA Cabinet Community Day on June 5, 2009, Governor Kaine and teachers speak about the Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics for Lifelong Initiatives for Education. Uploaded 1 July 2009.
    11:07 minutes
  - 56. Lunch on the Lawn - the Southwest Virginia Museum, 5 June 2009.
    On June 5, 2009, as part of his fourteenth Cabinet Community Day, the Governor and members of his Cabinet and Senior enjoyed lunch at The Southwest Virginia Museum and listened to music. Governor Kaine joined the band on stage as a guest harmonica player. Uploaded 23 July 2009.
    9:02 minutes
  - 57. Federation of Virginia Food Banks Check Presentation, 29 July 2009.
    Virginia's Governor Tim Kaine presents a ceremonial check for $1 million to representatives of the Federation of Virginia Food Banks. Governor Kaine recommended the money as a budget amendment. Uploaded 5 August 2009.
    8:32 minutes
  - 58. Statement of Virginia's Governor Tim Kaine on Pending Clemency Requests of the Norfolk Four, 6 August 2009.
    Statement of Virginia's Governor Tim Kaine on pending clemency requests of Danial Williams, Derek Tice, Joseph Dick and Eric Wilson. Uploaded 6 August 2009.
    33:02 minutes
  - 59. Governor Kaine announces Plan to Address Fiscal Year Revenue Shortfall, 8 September 2009.
    Virginia Governor Timothy M. Kaine announced his executive spending reduction plan to meet the FY 2010 revenue shortfall of $1.35 billion. Uploaded 8 September 2009.
    16:25 minutes
  - 60. Governor Kaine announces Amnesty Period on Delinquent Taxpayers, 28 September 2009.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine helped launch Get Square VA, a program administered by the Virginia Department of Taxation offering amnesty to delinquent taxpayers who pay their back taxes between October 2009. Uploaded 28 September 2009.
    8:14 minutes
  - 61. Virginia is for Lovers Wins National Walk of Fame Award, 23 September 2009.
    On September 23, 2009, Governor Timothy M. Kaine celebrated the "Virginia is for Lovers" slogan's induction into the National Advertising Walk of Fame. The honor coincides with the 40th anniversary of the slogan. Uploaded 21 October 2009.
  - 62. Governors College and Career Readiness Summit, 4 January 2010.
    Governor Timothy M. Kaine delivers remarks at the Governors College and Career Readiness Summit. The Summit was co-hosted with the Southern Regional Education Board. Governor-Elect Robert F. McDonnell delivered closing remarks for the summit. Uploaded 4 January 2010.
    1:31:21 minutes
  - 63. Governor Tim Kaine's Portrait Unveiling, 5 January 2010.
    Governor Tim Kaine's portrait is unveiled at the Library of Virginia. Uploaded 5 January 2010.
    28:13 minutes